Basic principles:
基本原则…
No woman wakes up saying:
没有女人起床时会说…
"God, I hope I don't get swept off my feet today."
“希望今天不会有帅哥追我”
Now, she might say, "This is a really bad time for me."
她可能会说：“现在时机不太对”
Or something like, "I just need some space."
或是这句：“我只是需要一点空间”
Or my personal favorite:
或是我最喜欢的…
"I'm really into my career right now."
“我现在正在全心发展事业”
You believe that? Neither does she.
你相信吗？她也不信
You know why? Because she's lying to you, that's why.
知道原因吗？   因为她在骗你
You understand me? Lying.
听懂了吗？骗你的
It's not a bad time for her. She doesn't need any space.
时机并没有不对    她也不需要空间
She may be into her career...
她也许专心事业…
but what she's really saying is, "Get away from me now."
但她其实是说：“给我滚开”
Or possibly, "Try harder, stupid."
或是：“再努力点吧，笨蛋”
Well, which one is it?
到底是什么意思呢？
60% of all human communication is nonverbal.
人类沟通有六成不是靠说话
Body language.
身体语言
30% is your tone.
三成靠你说话的音调
So that means that 90% of what you're saying...
那表示你的意思传达中有九成…
ain't coming out of your mouth.
不是用嘴巴讲的
Toby!
托比！
Shit!
糟了！
Of course she'll lie to you.
她当然会骗你
She's a nice person, she doesn't wanna hurt your feelings.
她是个好人，她不想伤害你
What else is she gonna say? She doesn't even know you.
她还能说什么？她跟你又不熟
Yet.
还不熟
Luckily, the fact is that just like the rest of us...
很幸运地，和我们一样…
even a beautiful woman doesn't know what she wants until she sees it.
就算美女也不知道自己要什么
And that's where I come in.
这就是我的工作
My job is to open her eyes.
我要让她看清楚
Oh, my God!
我的老天！
Is this what you're looking for?
你在找它吗？
Basic principles: No matter what, no matter when, no matter who...
基本原则：不论何事、不论何时、不论何人…
any man has a chance to sweep any woman off her feet.
任何男人都有机会迷倒任何女人
Just needs the right broom.
只要方法正确
You cannot use what you do not have.
你不能运用你没有的东西
So if you're shy, be shy. If you're outgoing, be outgoing.
保持自我，害羞的就别装外向，外向的别装害羞
- I'm not outgoing. - That's okay.
我并不外向     那无所谓
She may not want the whole truth, but she does want the real you.
她不想知道细节，但她要真正的你
She may not want to see it all at once, but she does want to see it.
她也许不会想一次搞定    但她想看真正的你
So tonight, when you're wondering what to say, how you look, or if she likes you...
所以今晚，当你在想该讲什么、该穿什么、或她到底喜不喜欢你时…
just remember, she is already out with you.
记住，她已经跟你约会了
That means she said yes when she could have said no.
那表示她在能拒绝时却答应了你
That means she made a plan when she could have just blown you off.
在她可以躲开你时却见了你
So that means it is no longer your job to try to make her like you.
这表示你不用再设法让她喜欢你
It is your job not to mess it up.
而是设法别搞砸一切
The shoes are hot. You went to the place I told you?
真赞的鞋，你照我说的去做了？
Yeah, but I don't think they're really me.
对，但是我不觉得我适合这样
"You" is a very fluid concept right now.
个人形象是很具可塑性的
You bought the shoes. You look great in the shoes.
你买了鞋，穿起来也帅呆了
That's the you I'm talking about.
那就是你的形象
The key tonight is hang back.
今晚的策略就是要放轻松
Give her plenty of space.
给她充份的空间
If she lingers at a photograph, move on.
她若流连在照片之前，继续走
But maintain the visual.
记得保持在视觉范围内
It's supposed to be 64 and clear tonight. So when you leave the club, walk a little.
今晚天气晴朗又凉爽    你们离开酒吧时，散个步
Ask her what she thought about the show...
问她对今晚的展览有何感想？
what was her favorite photograph, why that one.
她最喜欢哪一幅？为什么？
And when she answers, don't be looking at her mouth.
她回答时，别盯着她的嘴唇看
Don't be wondering what she looks like naked.
别幻想她光着身子的样子
Listen to what she is saying and respond.
倾听她说的话，有所回应
Listen and respond.
倾听、回应
That way, when it's your turn to talk...
那样轮到你讲话时…
you'll have something better to say than, "I like your mouth."
就不用说：“我喜欢你的嘴”
What was your favorite one?
你最喜欢哪个？
The elephant, definitely.
那幅大象，当然
And all of a sudden, we're on date number two.
突然，你就进入第二次约会了
Ready.
准备好了
No way.
不会吧
We're going back in there. You have to smile.
我们重照一次，你要笑啦
In case you didn't go to high school, hitting is a good thing.
没上过高中的可能不知道来电的感觉很棒
So how does it happen, great love?
那是怎么发生的？永恒的爱？
Are you okay?
你还好吧？
- Nobody knows. - I'm good.
没人知道     我很好
Let me get a Bomb Pop and a Screwball for the lady.
我要火箭冰，小姐要果冻冰
But what I can tell you, is that it happens in the blink of an eye.
我只能告诉你     爱总是发生在转眼之间
One moment, you're enjoying your life.
这一刻你还在享受人生
And the next, you're wondering how you ever lived without them.
下一刻却怀疑自己没有爱会死
Three dates is all I need.
我只需要三次约会
Three dates, and I'll get you here, to the high-stakes medal round...
三次约会，保证成功，我会让你达到致胜的关键时刻…
where eight out of 10 women believe that the first kiss...
十个女人之中有八个相信初吻…
will tell them everything they need to know about the relationship.
能传达出两人关系的一切
After that, you're on your own.
在那之后，一切就靠你自己了
But always remember...
但是请永远记住…
life is not the amount of breaths you take.
人生的本质不在于你活了多久
It's the moments that take your breath away.
而是那些令你怦然心动的时刻
Did I call it or did I call it?
我不是说过了吗？
I mean, what did I say, six months?
我说多久？六个月？
And when was her first date?
她第一次约会是什么时候？
So five-and-a-half? God, I hate it when I'm right.
那就是五个半月了？我还真准
What is it about guys that makes them want to screw anything that walks...
男人为什么老爱搞七捻三？
even when they're going out with someone as awesome as Allegra Cole?
交到奥丽格拉这种美女还不满足？
She's only the most fabulous thing walking around New York.
她是纽约最美的女人了
Thanks, Young.
谢谢
Are you kidding? Of course I'm gonna run it.
开什么玩笑？    我当然要写
Why should she waste her heart on some Swedish aristo-brat?
她干嘛去爱一个瑞典劈腿猪？
Even if he is gorgeous.
就算他是帅哥也一样
If he's stupid enough to cheat...
该让全世界…
the world should know he's dumb enough to get caught.
知道他干的蠢事
Exactly. I'm in the elevator. See you in a minute.
没错，我进电梯了，待会见
Good morning, how are you?
早安，你好吗？
Bitter, party of one.
不好，渡假的又不是我
You should try it sometime.
你该去渡假的
Barbados by myself? I wouldn't last five minutes.
自己去？我撑不到五分钟的
It was just what the doctor ordered.
我只不过是遵循医生的指示
I slept in, I did my yoga, I read a couple of books...
我睡大头觉、做瑜珈、看书…
flirted with my scuba instructor.
还跟潜水教练打情骂俏
- And apparently never left the office. - I know, isn't that great?
而且还不忘工作，那不是很棒吗？
You should've taken someone with you.
你该找个伴一起去的
Who am I gonna take with me?
找谁一起去？
This is where a boyfriend comes in handy.
所以该交个男朋友啊
- I don't have time for a boyfriend. - You said that two years ago.
我没时间交男朋友    这话你两年前就说过了
Yes, and it's as true today as it was then.
对，现在情况还是一样
I thought you were on vacation.
我以为你去渡假了
See if these are in focus and have them in my desk in an hour.
看这些照片清不清楚，我要用
Besides, relationships are for people waiting for something better to come along.
感情是给企求美好人生的人谈的
Spoken like a true cynic.
这么说真酸葡萄
I'm not a cynic. I'm a realist.
不是酸葡萄，是务实
You are a realist masquerading as a cynic who is secretly an optimist.
你是假装酸葡萄的务实份子
What are you doing here? What is she doing here?
你怎么在这里？她怎么在这里？
She works here, remember?
她在这里工作，记得吧？
No, she doesn't. Not for another four days.
那要再过四天以后
- This couldn't wait. - It could.
这条新闻等不得    当然可以
What are you doing? Go back to the beach.
你在这干嘛？     回海滩去渡假
- I don't want you here. - No, really, you do.
我这里不需要你     不，你需要的
You are becoming a sick, workaholic lunatic...
你成了一个超级工作狂
and this is exactly...
正是这种…
the kind of nervous, overwrought behavior that leads to...
过度紧张的行为让你...
Pictures of Sebby with a busty brunette.
拍到赛比跟波霸美女出游
A very big raise.
得到大幅度的加薪
Jesus. You could find dirt in a snowstorm.
天哪，你真有本事
Comes with the job.
这是我的工作
You know, kiddo, there is more to life than watching other people live it.
人生有很多比八卦还重要的事
Can I help he was cheating on my beach?
是他跑到我的沙滩上偷情的
I think it's great that you're so good at your job.
你这么专业很好
I'm just a little worried as to why.
我只是有点担心你
Let me worry about that.
让我自己来担心吧
Okay. I want that column on my desk by lunch.
好，我中午就要那篇报导
So you'll pay for my hotel?
那你会帮我付渡假的费用吧？
For you to sip mai tais? I don't think so. Get out.
请你喝鸡尾酒？    才怪，出去吧
- Come on. - What?
不会吧！    怎样？
- That's good, right? - No.
那球算进吧？    才怪！
No, it was in and it freaked out.
它本来要进袋，却突然转向
You know what your problem is, Hitch? You're all about the short game.
情圣，你的眼光就是不肯放远点
You pick your shots based on what you see first...
永远只看眼前…
not what's necessarily best for you...
而不是就长远看来…
in the long run.
最有利的选择
All of us are not married to the woman of our dreams and about to have a baby.
不是所有人都能娶到梦中情人，还即将生下宝宝
You know, I'm very happy for you. Just not meant for everybody.
我为你高兴，但那不适合所有人
So please just leave me to my hot, sweaty...
拜托你，让我玩个爽…
totally varied, wildly experimental short game.
打个短暂却高潮迭起的球局吧
- I was talking about pool, but whatever. - Yeah, okay.
我说的就是打球啊     随便啦
Honestly, I just hope one day you're able to experience...
我只希望有天你能经历到…
the unconditional love, trust, and openness...
无条件的爱、信任和坦承…
that I share with Grace every single day.
就像我和葛蕾丝一样
- Is this really barroom talk? - You need to listen to me. I'm serious.
男人在酒吧会谈这个吗？    听我的，我是说真的
Because when you get to a place with a woman like that...
等你找到一个这样的女人…
it's so beyond anything physical that...
那将会超越任何肉体关系…
when I think back to when I used to run around with you...
超越你我之前追过的…
and chase all these really gorgeous but shallow women...
任何一个波大无脑的妹…
I don't know, it's kind of ridiculous and vaguely pathetic.
我不知道，那有点荒唐，还有点可悲
Yeah, I see what you mean. That's pathetic.
是啊，我明白你的意思   那真可悲，太可悲了
So, how'd you meet him?
你怎么认识他的？
I was in La Perla just buying some weekend thongs.
我去买丁字裤的时候
- And he was doing likewise? - No.
他也去买丁字裤？    不是啦
Actually, he said he was buying something for his mom.
是啦，他说他是去买东西送他妈
His mom?
他妈？
Casey, who buys high-priced lingerie for their mother?
谁会买高级内衣给自己老妈？
Well, maybe he was looking for a robe.
也许他是想买睡袍
Casey, he was hitting on you while he was buying lingerie for another woman.
崔希，他在买内衣送其他女人时看上了你
- I prefer the mother story. - I know you do, but that's not the point.
我比较喜欢老妈这个藉口     我知道你喜欢，但那不是重点
No, the point is I'm not gonna start out assuming the guy's a liar.
不，重点是我不想假设他是骗子
- Why not? - Because that's how you wind up...
为什么？    因为那下场就跟你...
Like me? Is that what you were gonna say?
跟我一样？你是不是要说这个？
No. I was gonna say, "Like you."
我是说跟“你”一样
- What's his name? - Why?
他叫什么名字？    干嘛问？
- I'm gonna Google him. - No. Google your own guy.
我要上网查他     不要，查你自己的男人吧
Let's just see if his mother's still alive.
我只想查查他妈是不是还活着
- So when is Grace due again? - Soon.
你老婆预产期是何时？     快了
- You excited? - What'd you say?
你兴奋吗？      你说什么？
Do you want me to go get them and bring them over here?
要不要我去带她们过来？
No, don't do that.
不，别那样
Are you saying you don't wanna talk to them because you can't go home with them?
不能带回家就不玩了？
I'm just trying to keep my head above water.
我只是想保持清醒
- Have you heard of the Date Doctor? - Urban myth.
你听说过“约会顾问”吗？     那只是都市传说
- Really? - Absolutely.
真的？      当然
I was hoping he also helped women.
我还希望他也帮女人呢
Casey, you're not sick. You're single.
崔希，你没病，你只是没伴
You just have to relax and enjoy the ride.
你要放轻松，享受单骑人生
I haven't been ridden in months.
我好几个月没被人骑过了
On that happy note, I'm gonna go see if anybody interesting came in tonight.
你有病，我们谈得真愉快  我去看有没有有趣的人来这里
- You mean, besides me. - Right.
你是说除了我之外       对
Bye.
拜
I'll go get those girls, bring them over here...
我去带那些美眉过来…
and we'll have a conversation like human beings.
一起礼貌的聊个天
Then you're gonna home, and I'll take them back to my apartment.
然后你回家，我带她们回去
Well, that sounds like fun for me. But you might want to get in line, pal.
听来不错，但你可能得排队了
- Hey, girl. - Hey, how are you?
小姐！      你好啊
Hey, baby, can I get a couple Coronas at the pool table, please? Thanks.
小姐，送两瓶可乐娜去球台旁，抱歉
Excuse me.
对不起
Lime wedges in the bottle's fine.
柠檬塞进瓶子里就好
Hey, asshole, I don't work here.
猪头，我不是服务生
I'm sorry. The paramedics will have to come to get my foot out of my mouth, sweetheart.
对不起，这下我真是糗大了
Just don't let it happen again.
别再弄错就好了
- I knew you didn't work here. - You did?
我知道你不是服务生       你知道？
How else was I supposed to get you away from all those guys?
不然要怎样才能把你弄出来？
Why would you want to do that?
你为什么要这样做？
Some guys naturally develop a comfort with the opposite sex.
有些人天生就很会安抚异性
They like women, women like them. Everything flows naturally.
他们喜欢女人、女人也喜欢他们，一切浑然天成
Back in college, I was just not one of them.
在大学时代，我可差多了
I seemed to lack the basic understanding...
同学们早就忙着把妹时…
that my peers just intuitively grasped.
我却啥都不懂
But like any late bloomer, I was eager to make up for lost time.
而晚熟的我，急着想填补失去的岁月
Her name was Cressida Baylor.
她叫克芮丝德
Can you tell me where the registration building is?
麻烦你告诉我注册组在哪？
And my life would never be the same.
我的人生从此彻底改变
- I'm Alex. - Cressida.
我是阿圣    克芮丝德
What we had was beautiful.
我们的爱很美
I love you.
我爱你
I love you so much.
我好爱你
I love you, too, Alex.
我也爱你
I know you don't love me as much as I love you.
我知道你不像我爱你那般爱我
But that's okay. I'm just glad you love me at all.
但是没关系    我很高兴你爱我
In retrospect, I guess I may have come on a little strong.
回想起来，我也许是爱过头了
But the experience taught me a lot.
不过经验使我成长
Cressida!
克芮丝德！
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
I'm sorry, Alex.
对不起，阿圣
But I love you. What did I do wrong? Just tell me what I did wrong.
我爱你，我做错什么了？告诉我
You're doing it right now.
你现在就做错了
Alex, I'm sorry.
阿圣，对不起
And it's an education I feel obliged to pass on to my fellow men.
我觉得有义务要将这样的经验，传承给我的男性同胞
Because with no guile and no game, there's no girl.
因为若是没有技巧或本领，就把不到妹
If ever a man born was without game...
世上若有天生没本领的男人…
it was Albert Brennaman.
艾伯特布列曼就是了
My business is 100% referral and, thus far, untraceable.
我的客户全是推荐来的，到目前为止都难以追踪
And if there's one thing I've learned...
要说我有学到什么…
when you orchestrate, coordinate, and otherwise mess with fate...
那就是在你调整甚至改变命运时…
it's best to fly under the radar.
最好保持低调
I hope she's single 'cause I don't do break-ups.
老天   希望她是单身，我不拆散情侣的
Hi. Thank you for seeing me.
谢谢你来见我
Yeah, no. I mean, she just got out of a relationship.
是啊，她刚结束一段感情
Is that a problem? Because if it is, that's fine.
有问题吗？不行的话就算了
I'm a little uncomfortable with this anyway.
反正我也觉得这样有点怪
Definitely been hurt a lot. I had a lot of bad experiences.
我受过很多伤害    我的失恋经验一箩筐
Some good ones. But definitely a lot of bad ones.
有些经验还不错，但大多都很糟
I'm desperate, basically. I mean, not in general, you understand?
我很绝望，她不是一般女人
You know, not just for anybody. But, man, for her... Yeah.
普通男人根本配不上她
Why don't you tell me about her?
跟我谈谈她吧
Let's see, what can I say?
我能说什么呢？
My company handles her finances. I'm her tax consultant.
我们帮她理财，我是税务顾问
Well, I'm one of them. I'm the junior man on the account.
我是她理财团队里的一员
- So does she know you're interested? - No.
她知道你喜欢她吗？     不知道
Alive?
她知道你吗？
I lent her my pen once.
她用过我的笔
Shoot. Does anyone have a pen?
真是的，有人有带笔吗？
- Here, take mine. - Albert, you're crushing my arm.
这里     艾伯特，你压到我的手了
Sorry about that. Here you go, Allegra.
抱歉，拿去吧，奥丽格拉
Allegra? As in Allegra Cole?
这个奥丽格拉，不是奥丽格拉珂儿吧
Yeah, I realize that I'm not her usual type.
我知道我不是她喜欢的那型
Well, her last boyfriend owned Sweden or something.
她上一个男友，拥有整个瑞典
And that guy was a bum.
那家伙是个瘪三
He didn't seem like a very nice person to me.
看起来也不是个好人
You swing for the fence.
你还真有胆啊
Look, you don't think I tried talking myself out of this?
你以为我没设法打消念头？
I mean, you don't think I know how ridiculous this is? I know, okay?
你以为我不知道这有多荒唐？    我知道
I just thought that maybe with your help...
我只是想也许有了你的帮忙…
You know what? I'm really sorry I wasted your time.
真是的，抱歉浪费你的时间
Hold on a second, Albert.
等一等，艾伯特
You know what it's like getting up every morning feeling hopeless?
你知道我每天起床有多难过？
Feeling like the love of your life is waking up with the wrong man?
感觉就像你的挚爱跟错了男人
But at the same time, hoping that she still finds happiness...
但你又希望她找到幸福…
even if it's never gonna be with you?
就算她不是跟你在一起
You are flat-out...
你的头壳…
out of your mind. You know that?
真的坏了     你知道吗？
That's good.
这样很好
It is?
是吗？
You ever heard of Michelangelo?
听说过米开兰基罗吗？
Heard of the Sistine Chapel?
听说过西斯汀教堂吗？
Michelangelo.
米开兰基罗
Sistine Chapel.
西斯汀教堂
You saying you can do this?
你是说你办得到？
My name is Alex Hitchens. Let's go paint that ceiling.
我叫情圣耶，准备征服情海吧
Take it easy.
放轻松
Oh, my God!
我的妈呀！
Well, it looks like I'm still rich.
看来我还是很有钱
But what I would really like, and what I was wondering is...
但是我在想…
if I could have $500,000 to invest on my own.
我想做一个五十万的投资
And what were you thinking of investing in, Allegra?
你想投资什么呢？
Well, it's something that I really have a passion for.
是我很有兴趣的东西
Daydreams are for private time.
私人的梦想
When you're in the room, be in the room.
开会时要保持头脑清醒
Concentrate. Focus. Women respond when you respond to them.
集中思绪    你有回应女人就会有反应
My friend Maggie is a talented designer.
我朋友玛姬是个天才设计师
I've seen the business plan and the samples look fantastic.
我看过营运计划，样品也很棒
And I would really like to get involved.
我很想参与其中
I'll tell you what.
这样吧
Let us come up with a range of investments that we think you might be interested in...
我们先找一些有趣的投资案…
and next month, we'll run the whole lot of them by you.
下个月再拿给你看看
Okay.
好
Fine. Thank you. All right, gentlemen.
好了，谢谢各位
Let's go over this one more time. What is the objective?
再说一次    目标是什么？
Shock and awe.
突击致胜
That was shockingly awful. What is the objective?
真是有够小声，目标是什么？
- Excuse me, sir. - Yes, Albert?
抱歉     什么事？请说，艾伯特
I don't really agree with that.
我不太同意
You don't really agree with what?
你不太同意什么？
I think if you want to invest $500,000 in your friend's business...
你若想投资朋友五十万…
that's exactly what you should do.
那么你就该投资
You don't need us to tell you what to do.
不该由我们教你该怎么做
We're a board of advisers, not your kindergarten teachers.
我们是顾问，不是幼稚园老师
If you want to be taken seriously as an adult...
你想受人尊重…
then start taking yourself seriously
就得尊重自己…
instead of asking for permission to invest your own money...
不是想投资还要请别人同意…
from a boardroom full of your daddy's golf buddies.
而这些人还是你老爸的球友
- That's quite enough! - I'm not finished.
够了！      我还没说完
I'd like to see anybody in this room handle the attention and publicity...
我希望有人能适切的帮她处理…
that she's had to deal with her whole life, with half her class.
她这辈子都要面对的公关问题
We should be taking advice from you, Miss Cole. Not the other way around.
我们该聆听你的意见，而不是刚好相反
- Sit down... - No! You know what? I quit!
坐下…       不，我不干了！
Oh, my God.
我的老天
Just breathe. How'd it go?
别激动，结果如何？
I yelled at her. I screamed at my boss! I quit my job!
我骂了她、吼了老板！还辞职了！
- What? - You said...
什么？     是你说…
- I gotta go back. - No, I didn't tell you to quit.
我得回去       我没叫你辞职
Relax. Okay, listen, we're fine.
好了，没关系
- Would you let me go? - Albert, no!
放开我好吗？     艾伯特，不要
Just relax! Okay?
别激动！行吗？
- Just let it marinate for a second. Trust me. - No!
冷静一下，相信我       不！
Relax.
别激动、别激动
- It's Allegra Cole. - Answer it.
我是艾琳     开门
- Could I speak to you a second? - Answer the door, Albert.
能不能跟你谈谈？     快开门
Yes. Hi.
你好
What's up?
有事吗？
Listen, Albert, right?
你是艾伯特，对吧？
- People don't usually talk to me like that. - Close your mouth, man.
一般人通常不会那样跟我说话     把嘴闭上
Let me rephrase that.
我要修正这句话
People never talk to me like that.
一般人从来不那样跟我说话
Stand up.
站直
I guess it's kind of scary for them.
我想那是因为他们有点害怕吧
But that's why I really appreciate what you did in there.
因此我很感激你所做的一切
But I was wondering...
我在想…
do you think that you and I could get together sometime this week?
我们这礼拜能不能碰个面？
You know, to go over things.
你知道的，谈些事情
Financial things.
财务上的事
I'd like to see the areas where I can afford to take some risks.
我想知道我能承担多少风险
- Check your schedule. - I'll check my schedule.
查一下行程     我查一下我的行程
Great. Let me give you my number. Do you have a pen?
好，我把电话给你，你有笔吗？
I don't think I have one.
我没带笔
- Yes, I do. - Great.
我有     好极了
And call me Allegra.
还有，叫我艾琳就好
- You're done. - Goodbye.
没你的事了     再见
Good job.
干得好
Oh, damn.
不会吧
She's some kind of newspaper columnist. Comes in here once in a while. Great tipper.
她是报社专栏作家     偶尔会来，小费给得很凯
What's her drink?
她喝什么？
Usually beer. Tonight, Grey Goose martini, dirty.
通常是啤酒，今晚喝马丁尼
Hi.
你好
I noticed your glass was getting low...
我看你的酒快没了…
so I took the liberty of bringing you another apple martini.
所以我送一杯过来
Thank you.
谢谢
And I couldn't help but notice you look a lot like my next girlfriend.
你跟我下一任女友长得超像
- What's your name? - They call me Chip.
你叫什么名字？     朋友都叫我“晶片”
You can't get them to stop?
你没办法阻止他们？
That was funny.
你真风趣
Listen, I understand the courage it takes to walk across a room...
我明白走过来要鼓起多少勇气…
and try to generate a relationship out of thin air.
更别提还想设法制造气氛
- So don't take the following personally. - You have fantastic eyes.
别把我的话当成人身攻击     你的眼睛好美
Thanks. Try to listen.
谢了，听我说
This is no reflection on you. I'm just not interested.
这跟你无关，只是我没兴趣
But thank you for the compliment of coming over.
谢谢你这么看得起我
You're welcome. So do you like Cuban food?
不客气，你喜欢古巴菜吗？
Chip, seriously, that was not code for, "I wish you'd try harder."
说真的，我没有鼓励你的意思
Are you always so shut-down and afraid that the right man might make you...
你一向都这么冷若冰霜，害怕男人会让你...
Feel like a natural woman?
觉得自己是个天生尤物？
Sorry I'm late, honey. I couldn't get a cab. How was the meeting?
抱歉迟到，会开得如何？
Well, there was a beginning, a middle, and an end.
有开头、中间，也有结尾
Nice to meet you, Chip.
幸会了，晶片
You, too.
我也一样
On the one hand, it is very difficult for a man...
就某方面来说，男人很难…
to even speak to someone who looks like you.
跟你这种女人攀谈
But on the other hand, should that be your problem?
但另一方面     你该面对这些吗？
So life's kind of hard all around.
人生总是有逆境
Not if you pay attention.
只要多注意点就行
You're sending all the right signals:
你送出很清楚的信号…
No earrings, heels under two inches, your hair is pulled back...
没戴耳环、脚穿低跟鞋、头发绑在耳后…
wearing reading glasses with no book, drinking a Grey Goose martini...
戴眼镜却没看书     喝马丁尼…
which means you had a hell of a week and a beer just wouldn't do it.
表示你心情不好，啤酒不够看
If that wasn't clear enough...
更厉害的是…
there's always the "fuck off" that you have stamped on your forehead.
你脸上还写了“滚开”两个字
Who'd believe there's a man out there that can sit by a woman he doesn't know...
谁想到有个男人会坐到她身边…
and genuinely be interested in who she is, what she does, without his own agenda?
纯粹只是对她的身份感到好奇
I wouldn't even know what that would look like.
我真不知道有那种可能
So what would a guy like that say?
那个男人会说些什么？
He'd say, "My name is Alex Hitchens and I'm a consultant."
他会说：“我叫情圣，是个顾问”
But she wouldn't be interested in that...
但她不在意…
because she'd be counting the seconds until he left.
因为她在等他走开
Thinking he was like every other guy.
她认为他跟其他男人一样
Which, life experience has taught her, is a virtual certainty.
人生经验告诉她，一定是这样
But then he'd ask her name and what she did for a living...
当他询问她的姓名和职业时…
and she might blow him off.
她可能会赶他走
Or she might say...
或者她会说…
I'm Sara Melas. I run the gossip column at the Standard.
我是莎拉蜜拉丝   《标竿日报》的八卦专栏作家
And then he'd ask all these penetrating questions about her...
接着他会问试探性的问题…
because he was sincerely, if atypically, interested.
因为他是真的很感兴趣
No.
没有
- No? - He'd be interested.
没有？     他会有兴趣的
But he'd see that there was no way...
但他知道他没办法…
he could possibly make her realize that he was for real.
让她明白他是认真的
Well, he could be funny and charming and refreshingly original.
他可能风趣迷人又有创意
Wouldn't help.
那根本没用
- Don't you hate it when that happens? - Not really.
你讨厌这种情况吗？     还好啦
They'd both probably go on to lead the lives they were headed toward.
他们可能从此各过各的生活
My guess is they'd do just fine.
我想他们也会过得很好
It's a pleasure to have met you, Sara Melas.
很高兴认识你，莎拉蜜拉丝
Grey Goose martini from the gentleman who just left.
马丁尼，刚刚那位先生请的
Is that for me?
这杯是给我的吗？
What?
怎样？
Vance Munson. Sorry I'm late.
范斯孟森，抱歉我迟到了
No, not a problem.
不，没关系
Wow, you're the...
你就是那个…
- Can I get you something to drink, Mr... - No, I'm fine, thank you.
要不要来杯饮料…     不用，谢了
So, tell me about her.
谈谈她的事吧
Have you ever met someone...
你是否曾一见钟情…
and you knew right away she was gonna be important to you?
遇上你的真命天女？
Not just because of her looks, but that X factor.
不只因为她的外貌，还有别的致命吸引力
How'd you meet her?
你怎么认识她的？
Actually, I was in a shop buying pajamas for my mom.
我去买睡袍送我妈时认识的
And by that, of course, you mean...
那表示…
you were buying lingerie for another woman.
你是去买内衣送别的女人
Yes. You can't help where you meet somebody.
对，没错     邂逅的地点又由不得人选
And the lingerie is for a woman I'm no longer seeing.
我送内衣的那个女人也已经吹了
But anyway, the girl I met, the one I was talking about...
但我遇到的那个美眉…
she's so sweet, funny, Southern.
她甜美、风趣又有南方气息
She gives me her number. Now she won't return my phone calls.
她给我电话号码，却不回我电话
I don't know what it is about her. I just can't get her out of my mind.
我不知道怎么回事     我就是忘不了她
You know, food has lost its taste. Colors, they seem dull.
我食不下咽、世界色彩黯淡
Things that used to matter... I don't know, they just no longer do.
原本有趣的事…     却再也不有趣了
I think things aren't gonna snap back unless I...
我想一切不会恢复正常     除非…
Unless I bang her.
除非我上了她
Excuse me?
什么？
You know, bang her. Clear my head. Get in, get off, get out.
搞上她，满足我自己     进去、出来、走人
I think you may have misunderstood what I do exactly.
我想你可能误会我的工作了
No, I was told you help guys get in there.
有人跟我说你帮男人搞定女人
Right. But, see, here's the thing.
对，但这其中有所不同
My clients actually like women.
我的客户喜欢女人
Hit it and quit it is not my thing.
我不玩上床走人这一套
Let me make one thing clear to you, rabbi. I need professional help.
牧师，让我把话说清楚     我需要专业的协助
Well, that is for damn certain.
那很明白
And I'm glad you can admit it because generally that's the hardest part.
很高兴你能承认     这通常是最难的部份
You see what I'm doing? This is what I'm about.
看清楚了？这就是我
Power suit, power tie, power steering.
象征权力的西装、领带
People can wince, cry, beg, but eventually they do what I want.
人们会退缩、哭泣、恳求     但最后都会照我的意思去做
So that's, like, a metaphor.
所以那算是一种隐喻
Well, I'm more of a literal kind of guy.
没错，我这个人比较直接
So when I do this...
当我这样…
this is more like me saying that I will literally break your shit off...
就表示如果你敢再碰我…
if you ever touch me again. Okay, pumpkin?
我就会扭断你的手，明白吗？
Got it.
我明白了
No.
不
Pablo, I can't just mention your restaurant. Somebody has to eat there.
胖伯，我不能写你的餐厅， 有人要去用餐
No, somebody famous. You know that.
不，是名人，你知道的
- Sara Melas? - No.
莎拉蜜拉丝？     不行
Okay. Bye.
好，拜
I need your signature.
请签收
I hate it when a guy calls a girl who did not give him her number.
我讨厌打电话给没给电话号码的女人
So this is me not calling. Over.
所以我不用电话打，完毕
Yes, you're right. This is much less invasive.
你说得对，这比较不具侵略性
I've been thinking about that sign on your forehead.
我一直在想你脸上的字
And I was wondering if you'd mind taking it down for dinner Friday night. Over.
我想请你周五卸下心防共进晚餐     完毕
I can't. I have a couple of parties I have to hit.
不行，我要去参加几个派对
Gossip never sleeps.
八卦永远不打烊
Not till about 4:00 a.m.
凌晨四点才休息
Saturday.
周六
I have a date.
我有约会
Do you know the definition of "perseverance," Miss Melas?
你知道“不屈不挠”的定义吗     蜜拉丝小姐？
An excuse to be obnoxious?
惹人讨厌的一种藉口？
Continuing in a course of action...
持续某个行动…
without regard to discouragement, opposition or previous failure. Over.
不顾阻碍、反对或任何挫折     完毕
Okay, Webster, how do I get rid of you?
好吧，大字典，要怎样打发你？
Breakfast, Sunday. And you can barely even call that a date.
早餐，周日，那连约会都不算
You do that with out-of-town relatives that you don't even like. Over.
你跟不熟的人也会吃早餐，完毕
Come on.
去吧
Okay, I guess I could do Sunday.
好吧，我想周日可以
You forgot to say "over." Over.
你忘了说：“完毕”     完毕
This conversation's over as soon as you tell me when and where.
快说时间地点，我好结束通话
7:00 a.m., North Cove Marina. Over and out.
早上七点，北码头，通话结束
7:00 a.m.? Are you crazy? I don't do 7:00 a.m.
早上七点？你疯了？太早了
- Hello? - Sign here.
喂？     请签收
- What? - You said Sunday, right?
什么？     你说周日，对吧？
Yeah.
对啊
What if I would have said Friday?
要是我说周五呢？
Sunday.
周日
So I guess you're not going to church.
我想你大概不会去教堂吧
Do you really expect me to wear this?
你真以为我会穿这个？
Lt'll be awful cold out there without it.
在水里没穿这个会冻死
- Good morning. - "Good" would have been at 10:00.
早安     早上十点才是说“早安”的时候
You're a lot taller than I remember.
你比我记得的还高
You ever ride one of these?
你骑过这玩意吗？
Not on the Hudson.
没在哈德逊河上骑过
So, what do you wanna do? Race me around the Statue of Liberty?
你想干嘛？看谁先到自由女神像？
If there's time.
如果有时间的话
- But you might need these. - All right.
不过你可能需要这个     好吧
- Bam. - Wow.
帅啊     哇塞
How do I look?
我看起来如何？
Fabulous.
美呆了
All right, I give.
好吧，我投降
Where do I change?
我要到哪换衣服？
So we'll go past the wall, then take a left. It's pretty much a straight shot from there.
我们先骑出去，再左转，然后直走就能到了
- Straight shot to where? - That's for me to know and you to find out.
到哪里？     那就靠你去发掘了…
What you do with these babies is...
驾这玩意…
Yeah, what I do with this baby is kick your ass.
是啊，驾这玩意跟你拼了
- What happened? You change your mind? - It just died.
怎么？你改变主意了？     它挂了
Did you put gas in it?
你有加油吧？
No. You know, I think it must have sucked up a diaper or something.
我想它是吸进尿布之类的垃圾了
Gross. Try it again.
真恶心，再发动看看
You want me to call AAA?
要我找人来拖吊吗？
Come on around and let me hop on with you.
过来，让我跟你一起骑
I don't know. What if you break mine, too? Then we'll both be sitting ducks.
万一你也弄坏我的怎么办？     那我们就变成死鸭子了
- I didn't break it. It just died. - Yeah, yeah.
我没弄坏它，是它挂了     好啦，好啦
All right, hop on.
好吧，上来
- Scoot back. - Hitch, I'm already here.
往后坐     情圣，是我先坐在这里的
But you don't know where we're going.
但你不知道我们要去哪
Why don't you tell me? Then we'll both know.
告诉我不就成了
Man, male egos.
男人的自尊
I don't know how you guys make it through the day with them.
真不知道你们是怎么活下来的
What? It is not my ego.
干嘛？我才没有自尊问题
I just don't want to ruin the surprise.
我只是不想毁了惊喜
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
对不起，你没事吧？
There. I always keep a few of those around.
拿去，我身边都会准备几包
Thank you.
谢谢
I have lower back trouble. I just shove the ice packs right down there.
我下背部会痛     我会直接把冰袋塞进裤子里
No. That's a fresh one.
不…     那是新的
So, Ellis Island.
这是艾利斯岛
I have to admit, I have lived in New York my whole life and I've never been here.
我得承认我住纽约住很久了     却从未来过这里
I figured that. Most people haven't.
我想也是，大多数人都没来过
So I got my man Larry here to set us up a private tour.
我请赖瑞安排我们私下参观
- Great! - Anything for Hitch.
太棒了     为了情圣，什么都行
It was originally known as Oyster Island.
这里原名牡蛎岛
The island was expanded to its present size...
是在建地铁期间以挖出的废土…
with dirt removed during the construction of the New York subway system.
填充而成今日的规模
- Are you serious? - Yes.
真的？     是啊
- Did you know this? - Yeah. That's why I brought you here.
你知道吗？     知道，所以我才带你来啊
In fact, over 100 million Americans can trace their ancestry...
事实上，超过一亿美国人，都可以在旅客名册上…
back to a single man, woman, or child on the ship's manifest...
查到他们的祖先     当初只身飘洋过海…
to an inspector's ledger.
移民来此
By 1910, 75%% of the residents of New York...
在1910年     纽约、芝加哥、底特律…
Chicago, Detroit, Cleveland, and Boston...
克里夫兰、波士顿的居民…
were immigrants, or the children of immigrants.
有七成五都是移民或移民后裔
They generally lived in the poorest sections of the cities...
他们大多住在城里的贫民区…
in Little Italys, Chinatowns and other ethnic enclaves.
小义大利、中国城、还有其他少数民族区
It's called The Kissing Post.
这叫亲吻柱
The plaque explains how different cultures kiss after long absences.
这碑文解释了不同文化的人，在长久分离后如何亲吻爱人
Now, what exactly would qualify as a long absence?
怎样才叫长久分离？
I mean...
我是说…
- That count? - No.
那样算吗？     不算
I actually had a relative come through here.
我有个亲人是从这里上岸的
- Really? - Yeah.
真的？     没错
What?
干嘛？
- What? - What was that thing?
什么？     那是干嘛？
No. You know, I was just thinking...
没什么     我只是在想…
you can't really know where you're going until you know where you've been.
要面对过去才能昂首未来
- Ain't that right, Larry? - Amen, brother.
对吧，赖瑞？     没错，兄弟
That's kind of deep for a first date, don't you think?
初次约会讲这种话太深奥了吧？
What is that?
那是什么？
Oh, my God!
我的老天！
That's my great-great-grandfather. That's his signature.
那是我的曾曾祖父     那是他的签名
Jesus, it's right here!
老天，就在这里！
How did you know?
你怎么…     你怎么知道的？
Hitch did the search. I just found the page.
情圣查到的，我只是找出记录
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I saw that going differently in my mind.
在我想像中不是这种反应
So my family never saw him again. Well, except for on the Wanted posters.
我的家人再也没见过他了     只在“通缉要犯”传单上看过
Look, I'm really sorry.
我真的很抱歉
When I saw it on the computer, it said, "the Butcher of Cadiz."
我在网络上查到   “加地斯屠夫”
I thought it was a profession, not a headline.
我以为那是职业     不是头条新闻
It's just one of those horrible family legacies we've all tried to forget.
那是我们家族一直想忘却的丑闻
But thank you.
不过还是谢谢你
No, it was...
不，这真是…
- A train wreck. - No.
一场灾难，是啊     不是的
Let me get you a cab.
我帮你叫车
Thanks.
谢了
- Bye. - Bye-bye.
拜     拜拜
Taxi!
计程车！
Poor guy. Sounds like he went to a lot of trouble.
可怜的家伙，看来他搞砸了
It was fun. In a disastrous kind of way. I mean, this isn't exactly a hickey.
其实满好玩的，虽然有点惨     这其实一点也不浪漫
At least you got a good story out of it, right?
至少是个有趣的插曲     对吧？
Right?
对吧？
- You should try mine, it's great. - Wait. You're seeing him again?
你该尝尝我的，很好吃     等等，你还会再跟他见面？
Well, look, you said that I'm always expecting men...
你说过我老认为男人很烂…
to let me down, right? Assuming that they're gonna fail?
总让我失望，对不对？     老觉得他们会失败
Which he did.
他就失败啦
Yeah, but he did it with flair.
对，但他失败得很有本领
I mean, Case, he really tanked.
我是说，他真是一败涂地
And that's a desirable trait?
那算理想的特质吗？
Yeah. Weird, huh?
是啊，很怪吧？
Now, just keep it simple. Just like we practiced.
简洁有力，就跟我们练习的一样
We're just leaving a message.
我们只要留话
Women like Allegra Cole don't pick up numbers they don't recognize.
奥丽格拉这种名媛不会随便接电话
Hello?
喂？
She's on the phone!
她接电话了！
- Yes. Hello, Miss Cole? - Yeah.
你好，珂儿小姐？     是
Hi, I have Albert Brennaman for you.
艾伯特布列曼要找你
- One moment, please. - No. Tell her I'm at lunch.
请稍候     不！跟她说我去吃午饭了
We called her to tell her you're at lunch?
我们打电话告诉她你去吃午饭？
Allegra. Hi, it's Albert Brennaman.
奥丽格拉，你好，我是艾伯特
Hi, how are you?
你好吗？
Good. I'm doing good.
很好，我很好
The reason I'm calling is about our appointment this Wednesday.
我是想谈谈周三的会面
Not gonna be able to make it.
我不能去了
Well, when can you make it?
那你什么时候可以？
When can I do it?
什么时候可以？
I don't even know, because my whole next week is slammed.
不知道，我下周行程全满
Right. But it's all good.
对，但是没关系
No, we're gonna make it happen though, that's for sure.
不，我们可以见面     一定可以
We're going to make it happen. Yes.
我们还是会见面的
What's going on over there?
你那边怎么了？
Just moving some things around.
只是在搬东西
Sky Studios.
天际摄影棚
Tonight I'm actually going to this fashion thing at Sky Studios.
我今晚要去天际摄影棚看服装秀
Designer friend.
设计师朋友
I just thought it might be something your designer friend would be interested in.
我想你的设计师朋友玛姬，可能会有兴趣参加
Yeah, definitely.
是啊，当然
Well, great. Then I will put you back on with my...
好极了！我把你转接给我秘书…
- Allegra, over here, please. - Miss Cole, this way.
奥丽格拉，看这里     珂儿小姐，看这边
Great. One more.
老天，真对不起     没关系
- Hi, there. - This was a fantastic idea.
你好     这主意真是太棒了
I suppose. Hey, where's Maggie?
我也这么想，玛姬呢？
Late as usual.
习惯性迟到
Tonight I want you to meditate on the image of an iceberg.
今晚我要你想着冰山的样子
Do you know why I want you to do that?
知道这是为什么吗？
Because I'm cool?
因为我很酷？
- No. - I know, I'm not.
不是     我知道，我不酷
I'm saying that you are an iceberg...
你就像一座冰山…
in that over 90%% of your mass is below the surface.
有九成的体积隐藏在水面下
I know I'm heavy. I am.
我知道我很胖
I'm talking about who you are. It's a metaphor.
我说的是你的人，这是比喻
Accounting, business...
帐务、工作…
all of that is just a small part of a much deeper, richer Albert.
那只是一小部份     真正的艾伯特是更有内涵的
One more.
再来一张
It's gonna be loud in there...
那里会很吵…
so this is our opportunity to break the touch barrier...
你可以很自然的突破…
in a non-sleazy way.
碰触障碍
So get to where it's loudest. Ask her if she'd like a drink.
到最吵的地方去，问她要喝什么
Lean in, place your hand on the small of her back...
靠上去，把手放在她腰后…
and say it in her ear like a secret.
像说秘密一样的对着她耳朵问
Watch your hand placement. Too high says, "I just wanna be friends."
手放太高代表：“我只想当朋友”
Too low says, "I just wanna grab some ass."
太低代表：“我只对你有性趣”
Friends. Ass. Me.
朋友、性、我
Special issues: Allegra Cole is a celebrity...
注意：奥丽格拉是名人…
which means that when people talk to her, they'll ignore you completely.
别人跟她讲话时，会忽略你
She's classy, so she'll introduce you.
她很有教养，所以她会介绍你
When she does, shake hands hard and speak up. Let them know you're there.
到时你要用力握手、大声说话、让他们知道有你这个人
Show her you can handle being her escort.
表现出你可以做她的护花使者
- Egon, this is Albert. - How you doing?
伊哥，这是艾伯特     你好
- Albert, this is Zak. - Nice to see you.
艾伯特，这是萨克     幸会
These guys are friends with Maggie.
这些都是玛姬的朋友
- Been to that new Brazilian restaurant? - No, but I am...
去过那家新的巴西餐厅吗？     没有，但我想…
It's disgusting. I'm writing an article about it.
烂毙了，我要写篇评论
Did you see the new installation at MOMA?
你看到现代美术馆的装置没？
- Yes, did you think... - Disgusting.
有，你想…     烂毙了、烂毙了
Women can always tell when you're not being real with them.
女人知道你诚不诚实
Worst thing you can do is try to fake it, because you are a great guy.
你最好不要假装     因为你是很棒的对象
And you do have something to offer Allegra that no other man does.
你对奥丽格拉跟别的男人不一样
What was your name? Eggnog?
你叫什么来着？八哥？
Egon.
伊哥
What do you think of the design of the Jets' new football stadium on the West Side?
你觉得喷射机队的新球场如何？
Let me guess. Disgusting?
我猜猜看，烂毙了？
Think it over. We'll be back.
再想一想吧，我们马上回来
Thank you. I can't stand those guys.
谢谢，我真受不了那些人
Really? I kind of liked them.
真的？我还有点喜欢他们呢
But when all is said and done...
最后，今晚的主角…
tonight is not about Allegra.
不是奥丽格拉
- It's not? - No. Tonight is about Maggie.
不是吗？     不是，今晚的主角是玛姬
A woman's best friend has to sign off on all big relationship decisions.
闺中密友能左右两人的关系
So you can't afford to mess this up.
所以你绝对不能搞砸
Albert, I want you to meet my friend, Maggie.
我要你见见我朋友，玛姬
Hi, Maggie. It's an absolute pleasure to meet you.
玛姬，很高兴能认识你
I'm Maggie.
我才是玛姬
- No, you're not. - Actually, I am.
你才不是     我正是
Magnus Forester. Thank you so much for inviting us.
玛纳佛瑞斯，谢谢你邀请我们
- You have very soft hands. - Thank you.
你的手真柔软     谢谢
- Wow. So do you.
你的也是     谢谢
So tonight, you focus on one thing and one thing only.
今晚你只要注意做好一件事
Maggie.
玛姬
- Where does your inspiration come from? - Oh, my God.
你的灵感都是从哪来的？     我的老天
Anything I see.
任何事物吧
Something in a magazine, out on the street...
杂志里的报导     街上的东西…
in an old movie.
老电影里的情节
The receptive nature of the creative facility just astounds me.
创造力永远都能让我惊讶不已
Anybody want any spring rolls?
有谁想吃春卷？
That's a beautiful tie, by the way. This whole thing, it just works.
你的领带很棒，你的打扮很有型
Thank you.
谢谢
- Is he gay? - I don't think so.
他是同志吗？     我想不是
I like him.
我喜欢他
About the deejay. Generally, I have a firm no-dancing policy.
关于音乐，我严禁跳舞
But if she asks, you cannot say no.
但如果她邀你，你不能拒绝
I'm not worried about dancing. But if there are people there...
跳舞我不担心，但若有人…
I'm sorry, I hate to be a stickler, but I need to be thorough.
抱歉，我不喜欢挑剔，但我得掌握状况
Show me what you mean by you're not worried about it.
你说不担心，跳来看看吧
Trust me. You know what I'm gonna do.
相信我，我就是这样跳
That's what it's all about, right there.
这招超赞
See how it gets bigger?
动作开始变大
Now I'm gonna start the fire.
现在我要开始生火
But the feet are going. I start the fire, I make the pizza.
脚继续跳，我生火、做披萨
Hips are always going.
屁股不能停
Can't get enough hip.
用力给它摇下去
From there, the Q-Tip.
现在…     棉花棒
Q-Tip. Throw it away.
棉花棒…     丢掉
That's not working, hit them with this.
如果那招不行，就来这招
Don't ever...
不准再这样…
do that again.
跳舞了
Do you hear me?
听清楚了？
- Just expressing myself. - No.
我只是表达自我     不行
Not like that, you're not, all right?
那样根本不是表达自我     知道吗？
This is where you live.
你要这样跳
Right here.
这样跳
You live right here, okay? This is home.
就是这样，这样跳才对
None of this.
不要这样
I don't wanna see none of that.
我不要看到那招
Don't need no pizza. They got food there.
不用做披萨，那里有食物了
Elbows, 6 inches from the waist, 90-degree angles.
手肘离腰十五公分，成九十度角
Don't you bite your lip. Stop it.
别咬嘴唇
Women relate dancing to sex, all right?
女人把跳舞跟性联想在一起
Even a great dancer can lose it with one of these.
就算舞林高手用这招也逊掉了
Okay, now that's what I need to be learning.
看着，这样跳就好
Can't stop it.
我忍不住
You cannot stop it.
停不下来
Next subject.
下一个主题
Get out.
出去
Thanks.
谢谢
So, are you a Knicks fan?
你是尼克队的球迷？
When they're good.
他们打得好的时候是
- I'm really sorry. - Oh, God. Why?
我很抱歉     怎么了？
- She was there? - I left you a bunch of messages.
她去了？     我有留言给你
My phone fell in the Hudson.
我的手机掉到河里了
Yeah, well, it gets worse.
还有更糟的
I don't believe this.
我真不敢相信
- I thought he was a bodyguard. - I'm the only one who will need protection.
我以为他是保镳     这下需要保护的是我了
- Max is gonna... - Gonna be really irritated.
麦克斯他…     要发飙了
When I got the train this morning, I thought it was gonna be a good day.
我今早搭车上班时     还在想今天会很顺利
Who the hell is Albert Brennaman?
艾伯特布列曼是谁？
- Tell me how this happened. - What? There were some photographers.
这是怎么回事？     什么？那里有一些摄影记者
Does this even look like dancing to you?
你这样子像是在跳舞吗？
That's just a little bit of me being me.
那是我在展现一点点的自我
No, that's you being a lot of something you don't need to ever be again.
不，那是你在做一些，你永远不能再做的事
- It's just one dance. - No.
只不过是跳支舞嘛     不
One dance, one look, one kiss. That's all we get, Albert.
一支舞、一个眼神、一个吻     那是你仅有的机会
Just one shot to make the difference...
一次就造成天壤之别…
between happily ever after and:
不是从此幸福快乐，就是…
"Oh, he's just some guy I went to some thing with once."
“他只是个普通朋友而已”
All right?
知道吗？
- What? - You said "kiss."
怎样？     你刚刚说：“吻”
Is that a problem?
有问题吗？
It's not a problem, but this is Allegra Cole.
没问题，不过这是奥丽格拉珂儿
Eight out of 10 women believe that the first kiss...
十个女人有八个相信初吻…
will tell them everything they need to know about a relationship.
能传达出两人关系的一切
And believe me, she has definitely thought about it.
相信我，她绝对有想过这件事
- She has? - Of course.
她想过？     当然
Not that she's gonna act on it. So it's no real big deal.
那并不表示她会主动     所以那没啥大不了的
- All right, it's no big deal then. - It's a very big deal!
那就没啥大不了     这非常重要！
- Huge. - Monumental!
很重要     超重要！
You are not listening...
你没注意听…
I need you to wrap your head around this.
注意听着
Tomorrow night, Allegra Cole...
明天晚上，奥丽格拉…
could have her last first kiss.
会吻下她最后一个初吻
All right, come on, just show me what you got.
好了，让我看你会怎么做
- What do you mean? - Just show me how you would kiss me.
什么意思？     让我看你会怎么吻我
I wouldn't kiss you.
我才不会吻你
I'm not me, I'm Allegra.
我不是我，我是奥丽格拉
But you're really not, so...
但你真的不是，所以我…
Okay, Albert, end of the night, you're dropping me off at home.
好，约会结束，你送我回家
- Show me the magic. - I'm not comfortable with this.
展现魔法吧     这样让我很不舒服
God, Albert, I had such a wonderful time with you.
天哪，我跟你一起玩得很愉快
Yeah, how about those Knicks?
尼克队打得不错吧？
You see what I'm doing? This is a signal. I'm fiddling with my keys.
看到我的动作了？     这是一个讯号，我在玩钥匙
A woman that doesn't want a kiss...
不想被吻的女人…
takes her keys out, puts them in the door, goes in the house.
会直接拿出钥匙开门进屋
A woman that wants to kiss, she fiddles.
女人喜欢玩着钥匙等人吻她
I'm fiddling.
我在玩钥匙
Okay, you have a good night now...
你很愉快，而我…
- You see what I'm doing? - Robbing me?
知道我在干嘛？     你要抢我？
No.
不是
This is what most guys do. They rush in to take the kiss.
一般男人都会这样冲过去吻女人
But you're not most guys.
但你不是一般男人
See, the secret to a kiss is to go 90%% of the way...
亲吻的秘诀在于采取九成主动…
and then hold.
然后等待
- For how long? - As long as it takes...
等多久？     有多久等多久…
for her to come the other 10%% .
等她采取那另外一成的行动
Okay, 90%% -10%% . Got it.
好，九成、一成，我懂了
Okay, come on. Shake it off. It's your turn.
你懂了？好，放轻松，该你了
I had a really nice time tonight, Albert.
我今晚很开心，艾伯特
I had a great time tonight, too, Allegra...
我也是，奥丽格拉…
with a beard.
留了胡子的
What's up?
怎么了？
- I'm not feeling it. - What do you mean? I came 90%% .
我没感觉     什么意思？我做了九成
I'm not feeling like you want it.
我不觉得你想吻
Look, I'm Allegra Cole, the woman of your dreams.
我是奥丽格拉，你的梦中情人
The woman whose green eyes are limpid pools of desire.
她清澈的双眼是你的欲望之泉
Now, show me the magic, Albert.
展现魔法吧
- What the hell was that? - I'm showing you the magic!
你在搞什么？     魔法啊
No, I said come 90%% and then I come 10%%!
我说你做九成，然后我做一成
You don't go the whole 100%%!
你不能全包啊！
My mouth was open, Albert. You overeager son of a...
我嘴是开的，你也太饥渴了…
Other than that, how was it?
除那之外，我表现如何？
They came together, they danced together, and they left together.
他们一起来、跳舞、一起离开
He's cute, in a sheepdog kind of way.
他很可爱，像只牧羊犬
For all I know, he's adorable.
我知道他很可爱
But him dating her is...
但跟她约会…
You seem stressed.
你似乎很紧张
You and I had an understanding.
我们说好的
If you invite Allegra, you're supposed to call me.
你邀了奥丽格拉就该通知我
I didn't invite her.
我没邀她
Honestly, sweetie, I thought she was still in Europe.
我以为她还在欧洲
- So you invited Albert? - No.
那你是邀艾伯特了？     没有
Look, it says here the tickets went to some guy named Alex Hitchens.
票是给一个叫情圣的
What?
什么？
Machine.
答录机
Hi, it's Sara.
你好，我是莎拉
I just wanted to say thank you...
我只是想谢谢你...
for an unforgettable experience...
那天给了我一个…
the other day.
难忘的经验
And if you ever want to see your shirt again...
如果你想再看到你的衬衫…
you can come by the Fulton Fish Market tonight, around 8:00.
今晚八点来富顿鱼市
Okay, bye.
拜
- Do you think he'll show? - Yeah.
你想他会来吗？     会
He's too much of a player to have a bad date on his record.
这种情场高手讨厌受挫
Is this a source or a date?
这是要挖消息还是约会？
A source.
挖消息
Well, it sounded like a date.
听起来像是约会
Well, it was supposed to.
我是故意的
So it looks like a date and it sounds like a date...
它看起来、听起来都像约会…
- but it's not a date. - Yeah. Right.
但却不是约会     没错
Just checking.
我只是问问
Hi. I wasn't sure you got my message.
我还以为你没听到我留言
I wasn't sure you called the right guy. You must be a glutton for punishment.
我还以为你打错电话了     你一定很喜欢自虐
Either that or I really wanna pay you back.
或者是我真的很想报复
I think this is yours.
我想这是你的
Thank you. I'm gonna frame this for my wall of shame.
谢谢，我要把这挂在丢脸墙上
Really? There's a whole wall?
真的？你有一整面墙？
So what are we getting into?
我们今晚要干嘛？
Ever been to a food rave before?
你参加过美食讲座吗？
Happens once a month, all around the city. Different chefs, different venues.
每个月举办一次     不同的厨师、不同的地点
You any good in the kitchen?
你会烹饪吗？
I can stand the heat, if that's what you mean.
我不怕热
Good. Because that's my boss and his wife right over there.
很好，因为我老板跟他老婆就在那里
Interesting.
真有趣
Well, here's a concept: We're paying to cook our own food.
这是一个想法：我们付钱来煮菜
Here's another concept: Shut up. It's an evening out.
另一个是：闭嘴啦     我们是出来吃饭
The longer you're married, the less you go out.
结婚越久，就越不常出来吃
In a couple of years, we're gonna end up bricked into our apartment like a Poe story.
过几年我们就会关在家里发臭了
So, Louise, are you in the newspaper business, also?
露易丝，你也在报界做事？
No, I'm a psychiatrist.
不，我是心理医师
Well, that's the last thing I'm gonna say tonight.
那我就不多说了，以免被心理分析
So, Sara, you never told me.
莎拉，你怎么没跟我说
How was the Sky Studio fashion thing you went to the other night?
天际摄影棚那天的秀怎样？
Did you meet anyone worth mentioning?
你有遇到什么名人吗？
No.
没有
Really? I find that very odd.
是吗？真是怪了
- Max. - I think you're being odd.
老板     我觉得你才怪呢
Well, I'm always odd. It's why you married me.
我一向很怪，所以你才嫁给我
And it's why I married you.
这也是我娶你的原因
Speaking of which, Hitch...
说到这个，情圣…
what exactly are your intentions for the lovely Sara?
你对莎拉到底有何意图？
Wait, you know what? Actually, there was someone.
对了，其实我有遇到名人
I think I met your friends Albert and Allegra.
我遇到你朋友艾伯特跟奥丽格拉
- My friends who and who? - Allegra Cole?
他们是谁？     奥丽格拉珂儿？
Really? How do you know her?
真的？你怎么认识她的？
- I don't. - So you know Albert?
我不认识     那你认识艾伯特？
- Knew. - He had your tickets.
以前认识     他手上有你的票
I mean, how well do you really know your accountant?
会计师就是这样
April 15, and then you don't see him again till April 15.
报完税一整年都见不到他们
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位先生女士…
a coquille St. Jacques with a lemon butter reduction.
柠檬奶油扇贝
- Compliments of our chef. - Thank you.
大厨请的     谢谢
I'm sure you're really gonna enjoy this.
我想你们会喜欢的
That's really good.
真好吃
I'm very impressed.
我很讶异
Why is that?
为什么？
Around these two, people usually can't wait to name-drop and dish their friends...
你知道，在这两个人身边     人们都会拼命讲八卦是非…
and you're being all discreet.
而你却很低调
Yeah, it's quite endearing.
是啊，这还满讨喜的
Actually, it is. So why don't we change the subject?
是啊，我们换个话题吧？
- Are you all right? - Yeah. No, I'm fine.
你还好吧？     没事，我很好
So Sara tells me that you're a consultant, Hitch.
听莎拉说你是个顾问
Yeah, mostly marketing, little advertising, brand management.
是啊，大多是行销的案子     少数则是广告、品牌管理
I have no idea what that means.
我不懂什么是品牌管理
No one does. That's why I get to charge so much.
没人懂，所以我收费才那么高
Are you sure you're all right?
你真的没事？
Yeah, I'm fine. Is it itchy in here or is it just me?
我很好，这里怎么这么热？
- I know what's happening. - No.
我知道这是怎么回事     不
You think that I'm in a stressful state...
你以为我过度紧张…
because I'm trying to make a good impression...
因为我想一边谈恋爱…
while also dealing with my commitment issues...
一边给大家留下好印象…
trying to avoid all these awkward conversations.
同时还想避开这些麻烦的话题
No, I think you have food allergies.
不是的，我想你是食物过敏
- Wow. - What?
天哪     干嘛？
- Benadryl. Where's the Benadryl? - Aisle 2.
过敏灵放哪里？     二号走道
- Which one's Aisle 2? - The one with the big 2 over it.
哪一个是二号走道？     上面挂了二的那个
Sara, I'm fine.
莎拉，我没事
- You sure it's in Aisle 2? - No.
你确定是在二号走道？     不确定
Really, it is not that serious.
真的，没那么严重啦
Benadryl.
过敏灵！
- A lot of Benadryl. A lot. - What? Are you...
要买很多     什么？你干嘛？
Coquille St. Jacques. Death on a leaf!
柠檬奶油扇贝，简直是毒药！
Come on!
快啊！
Okay, we're doing fine.
好了，没事了
Just a couple more blocks and you get to lie down.
再走几条街你就能躺下了
Wait, who sings that song again?
这首歌谁唱的？
Oh, girl. Earth, Wind & Fire.
地风火合唱团
You should let them sing it.
你不该抢他们的饭碗
I bet this would be great on the rocks. It's good, right?
这加冰一定很好喝，对吧？
I bet I can ask you just about anything right now.
我想我现在可以问你任何事了
No.
不
I'm a vault, baby. Locked down.
我是保险箱，锁得超紧
What is an heiress doing with a CPA?
女继承人跟会计师在一起干嘛？
They're going to the Knicks game.
他们要一起去看尼克队比赛
Yep, Fort Knox.
没错，诺克斯堡
He loves her so much!
他超爱她的！
I'm sure he does.
我相信
I'm telling you, people search their whole lives trying to find the...
我告诉你，人们一辈子都在找寻…
Reasons that we're here
我们存在的理由
I wouldn't know.
我不知道
You would if you saw it.
等你看到你就会知道了
Sometimes it's really hard to see the forest through the sleaze.
这年头好男人真的很难找
What about you? You ever been in love?
你呢？你爱过吗？
Yep.
有
But you're never gonna know that.
但你永远不会知道的
Okay, I think you've had enough of the juice box.
我想你喝太多糖浆了
Let's go.
走吧
This is some place.
这里真不错
You live here alone?
你一个人住这？
Yeah. I actually prefer it that way. What about you?
对，我喜欢一个人住，你呢？
I haven't had a roommate since college, and he upped and married my sister.
我大学时代有过一个室友     他后来娶了我妹
- Really? - Yeah, they're gonna have a baby soon.
真的？     对，他们的小孩就快出生了
Uncle Hitch.
情圣舅舅
Thank you.
谢谢
- So, how do you feel? - Good.
你感觉如何？     很好
Relaxed.
很放松
So what about you? Any siblings?
你呢？有兄弟姐妹吗？
Sister. Maria. Lives in D.C.
有姐妹，玛莉亚，住华盛顿
Younger, right?
是妹妹吧？
I could hear it in your voice.
我从你声音里听得出来
Sort of an innate protective thing.
有点天生的保护味道
Yeah, I guess.
我想是吧
What?
怎么了？
She almost died once.
她以前差点死掉
I was 10.
我十岁的时候
We were skating on the pond behind our house...
我们在我家后面的池塘溜冰…
and she fell through the ice.
她跌入池塘的薄冰中
My dad pulled her out.
我爸把她拖出来
Gave her mouth-to-mouth.
帮她做人工呼吸
Longest three minutes of my life.
那是我这辈子最长的三分钟
Yeah, I'm sure.
我相信
I don't think I've ever really gotten over it.
我一直都没办法释怀
Kind of defines you, doesn't it?
这成了你的心结，对吧？
You know like, one moment you're gliding along...
前一刻你还无忧无虑的遨翔着…
the next moment you're standing in the rain watching your life fall apart.
接着却在雨中看自己的人生崩解
Except it was snow.
我是在雪中
Yeah. That's what I said, "snow."
是啊，我就是说“雪中”
You said "rain."
你是说“雨中”
Some kind of precipitation.
雪也是雨的一种形态
Is that what happened to you?
你遇过类似的事？
Nothing as dramatic as falling through the ice.
比不上跌落冰中这么精彩
You know...
你知道的…
it definitely...
那绝对会…
Left a scar?
留下疤痕？
Yeah.
没错
I guess it's best just not to love at all, right?
最好不要谈恋爱，对吧？
Or skate.
或是溜冰
Are you here?
你在吗？
Sara, you're such an idiot! You moron! What the hell did you think?
莎拉，你真白痴！     大蠢蛋！你在想什么？
You're so stupid! You gotta learn, Sara.
你真蠢！莎拉，你老毛病又犯了
- When are you gonna learn... - Should I come back later?
你什么时候才能学会…     我要不要等一下再进来？
Hi. I thought you left.
我以为你走了
Well, I did, but then I came back with breakfast.
我是走了，但我买了早餐回来
I figured it was the least that I could do.
我想我至少可以做到这点
I didn't know what you were drinking...
我不知道你喝什么…
so I got a grande cap, a latte, an Earl Grey tea...
所以我买了大杯卡布奇诺、拿铁、伯爵红茶…
and something with "chai" in the title.
还有什么奶的
Tea for me.
我喝茶
Tea. Yes! I was hoping you'd say that.
茶，好耶！我正希望你选茶
Oh, God. You're a morning person, aren't you?
天哪，你是早起型的人，对吧？
Well, like I always tell my clients:
我一向都告诉我的客户…
Begin each day as if it were on purpose.
每一天都要很有目标的开始
- Wow. Beautiful day. - Yeah.
真美的一天     是啊
- Beautiful girl. - Thank you.
真美的女人     谢谢
Well, I'm this way.
我往这边
I'm that way.
我往那边
Give me a ring sometime.
有空就来电吧
I mean, on the phone.
我是说打电话
No, I definitely will.
当然，我一定会的
Good.
好
I gotta go to work.
我得去上班
Bye.
拜
Goodbye.
再见
Can you believe what a beautiful day it is...
今天真是太…
not?
凄惨了
- What's wrong, pumpkin? - I'm so stupid.
怎么了？     我真蠢
I ignored your advice. I went on that date.
我不听你劝，跑去跟他约会
With who?
跟谁？
Not the lingerie guy.
不是那个内衣男吧
Vance Munson. And you're right, there's no way he ever had a mother.
范斯孟森，他根本不可能有妈
That bad?
那么糟？
He took me to Scalinatella, and he was affectionate and sweet.
他带我去高级餐厅，深情又体贴
He told me all these intimate things, like how he can't taste food...
他说了好多秘密     像他吃东西没味道…
and he wants three kids.
还有他想要三个孩子
So you slept with him.
所以你就跟他上床
I never seen anybody get dressed that fast.
我没看过跑那么快的男人
Case, I'm so sorry.
崔希，我好抱歉
- Maybe I'll just die alone after all. - No, you won't.
也许我会孤独老死     你不会的
You'll meet a great guy with a great smile and you'll travel the world together.
你会遇见一个有阳光笑容的男人     你们会一起环游世界
Who are you? Where's my best friend?
你是谁？我的好朋友呢？
It's true. He just hasn't found you yet. But he will.
他还没找到你，但他会找到的
Just as he's leaving, guess what he says: "Date Doctor, my ass."
他走时还说：“去他的约会顾问”
- What does that mean? - It means he's really out there.
那是什么意思？     那表示真有其人
And if I ever meet him, the only date he's gonna need is with a real doctor.
要是让我遇上他     他就等着去住院吧
That's him.
就是他
Vance, is that you?
范斯？是你吗？
Yeah, hey there, beautiful.
你好，大美女
Sara Melas, from the Standard.
《标竿日报》的莎拉蜜拉丝
I'd like to discuss the dating consultant you hired...
谈谈你跟崔希约会前…
before you went out with Casey Sedgewick.
找的顾问吧
You don't wanna talk, that's fine. I'm going to write this anyway.
你不想谈，好吧，我还是会写的
You just earned yourself a photo with a boldface caption.
你的照片等着上报了
What? Nice.
什么？这可好了
I can only imagine how the trading floor guys will react when they see this.
我能想像交易员们，看到这条新闻的反应
You have no proof, no facts.
你没有凭据、没有事实
Vance, I'm a gossip columnist, not the DA.
我是八卦记者，不是检察官
Okay, how much will it cost me to stay out of this?
我要花多少钱才能摆平这事？
I don't want money. I want a name.
我不要钱，我要名字
- I don't know his name. - Well, what do you know?
我不知道他的名字     那你知道什么？
I know this.
我知道这个
All this for a lousy lay.
就为了一个不怎样的女人
Are we satisfied?
满意了吗？
Almost.
差不多了
No, you... You got to be...
你...     你不会吧…
Is this really necessary?
这真的有必要吗？
Have you seen your back?
你看过你的背吗？
No, but I see my front and maybe we should be starting with some sit-ups.
没，但我的前面需要雕塑一下
God! Mother of Troy!
天！我的妈呀！
Hello?
喂？
That's crazy. Just hearing your voice makes me smile.
真疯狂，你的声音让我想微笑
How are you?
你好吗？
I'm good, I think.
我想我很好
No, actually, you know what? I feel a little strange.
不，其实我有点奇怪的感觉
I'm good.
我很好
Sweet Georgia Brown!
阿娘喂呀！
What was that?
那是什么？
No, that's just some guy screaming.
只是有个男人在鬼叫
Listen, is there any context...
你想脸部变形跟逛药房…
under which you'd consider facial edema and pharmaceutical intervention a date?
跟约会有任何关系吗？
Probably not.
也许没有吧
How about a do-over?
再试一次吧？
- What do you have in mind? - Dinner, my place.
你有何计划？     晚餐，在我家
Because obviously going anywhere public with you is out of the question.
因为跟你出去用餐显然会出事
God! That's it. I don't like you very much.
够了，我讨厌你
What is that?
那是什么？
Wait, I'm getting up.
不，我要起来
It's like one of those makeover shows.
是那种玩整形的电视节目
- That's a makeover show? - It's Danish.
那是整形节目？     丹麦的节目
Almost done!
就快好了！
Friday?
周五好吗？
Can't. I told a friend I'd go speed dating. You know, for moral support.
不行，我跟朋友要参加快速约会     我要去陪她
But tomorrow I'm free.
不过我明天有空
Great. All right, 8:00?
很好，那就八点？
Great.
好
- All right. Bye-bye. - Bye.
好，拜拜     拜
- See, it wasn't so bad, was it? - God!
没那么糟嘛，不是吗？     妈呀！
Ball is back in play after a 20-second timeout.
球赛暂停20秒
Knicks lead the Grizzlies, 12-6, here early in the first quarter.
尼克队第一节前半以12比6领先
- So this is what this feels like? - "This" being?
原来就是这种感觉啊     你是指？
Great seats, great game.
绝佳的座位、绝佳的比赛
Great date.
绝佳的约会
I mean, sort of.
我是说，算约会吧
To me, it feels like a...
对我而言，感觉就像…
- Date? - Yeah.
约会？     是啊
Look at her. She looks so happy.
看看她，她很快乐
How does a guy like that end up with a girl like her?
这种人怎么会搭得上她？
I am so jealous. I've always wanted to be able to do that.
我好嫉妒，我一直想那样吹
Really? Tonight is your lucky night. Let's see what you got.
真的？算你走运，吹给我看看
Okay. You ready?
准备好了？
- Oh, God. I'm sorry. - It's fine.
老天，真对不起     没关系
Knicks off to a great start...
尼克队一开始打得不错…
All right, here's how it works.
好吧，你听着
Central Park Zoo, tomorrow, noon, by the sea lions.
中央公园动物园     明天中午，海狮前见
No, don't worry. I'll find you.
不用担心，我会找到你的
All right. Thank you.
好，谢谢
It's all right. I'm sorry.
没关系，对不起
Damn me.
我真该死，该死！
That was it! You got it. Do it again.
就是那样，你会吹了，再来一次     再来一次
Look how cute they are.
你看他们真可爱
Thanks.
谢了
I had a great time tonight, Albert.
我今晚很愉快
I had a great time, too, Allegra.
我也是
Good night.
晚安了
Good night, Albert.
晚安
- Allegra. - Yes?
奥丽格拉     什么事？
Hold on.
等等
I like your lips.
我喜欢你的嘴唇
They seem to like you, too.
它们也很喜欢你
Good night.
晚安
- Anything? - Not yet.
看到没？     还没
But I got some great shots of you biting your nails.
但我拍了你咬指甲的照片
Well, it's a big story.
这是条大新闻
- Incoming. - Really?
来了     真的？
Yep. They're shaking hands.
他们在握手
This is so great. I can't wait to nail this guy.
太棒了，我等不及要逮这家伙了
Make sure you get a good shot of his face.
拍清楚点
- What's he look like? - Tall, dark, and handsome.
他长什么样子？     高瘦、黝黑又英俊
Basic principles:
基本原则…
No matter what, no matter who, no matter when.
不论何事、不论何时、不论何人
This is killing me.
我快被闷死了
Geoff is managing to play it straight.
杰夫扮异性恋者满像的
How long have you been in love with her?
你爱上她多久了？
Her? About two-and-a-half years.
她？有两年半了吧
Take a look.
你看看
- How'd you get my card? - Albert Brennaman.
你怎么拿到我名片的？     艾伯特布列曼
- Great guy, isn't he? - Excellent guy.
他人很不错吧？     超正点的
What? Sara.
怎么？莎拉
- Pleasure to meet you, Geoff. - Hey, what...
很高兴认识你，杰夫     怎么？
- How'd you get my card? - Albert Brennaman.
你怎么拿到我名片的？     艾伯特布列曼
- Great guy, isn't he? - Excellent guy.
他人很不错吧？     超正点的
You sure you want to do this?
你确定你要写？
Why wouldn't I?
为什么不写？
Louise made an interesting observation on the way home the other night.
那天晚上露易丝在回家时，做了个有趣的观察
She said people who are guarded are afraid...
她说小心谨慎的人很害怕…
that you can see right through them.
人一眼看穿他们
That's why they hide behind layers of secrecy or humor.
所以他们躲在秘密和幽默之后
He'll have to hide behind a lot more than that once this hits the fan.
等这个见报之后，他有得躲了
She meant you.
她是说你
What do you want me to say?
你要我说什么？
That I like the guy? Yeah, sure, I liked the guy.
我喜欢这个人？好，我喜欢他
Well, here's his shirt.
这是他的衬衫
- Why don't you think about it? Call me. - Thanks.
你先想清楚再打个电话给我吧     谢了
Papi, Sara Melas is here to see you.
老爹，莎拉蜜拉丝来找你
Thanks a lot, Raoul. Send her up. And stop calling me papi.
谢了，让她上来，别叫我老爹了
Well, aren't you a sight for sore eyes.
你真是令人望穿秋水
I believe this belongs to you.
我相信这是你的
Yeah, this thing is like a bad penny.
这件衣服真爱搅局
Wow!
哇塞！
So this is it.
这里就是了
Yeah, this is it.
是啊
Business must be good.
你一定很赚钱
Well, it has its rewards.
你知道的，这行有这行的报酬
I'll bet.
我想也是
Tough day?
今天很倒楣啊？
You could say that.
可以这么说
Well, you know what? You can just sit back and relax.
这样吧，你放轻松
I got this all covered.
我会搞定一切
Spanish wine!
西班牙红酒！
How thoughtful are we?
你真细心
- Here, let me pour that for you. - No, that's okay.
来，我帮你倒吧     没关系
- You want some? - Sure.
你要喝吗？     好啊
So, Hitch.
“情圣”
Is that a noun or a verb?
这是名词还是动词？
I guess it depends.
看情况
Let's see, what should we toast to?
我想想，我们该敬什么？
Never lie, steal, cheat, or drink.
绝不说谎、偷窃、欺骗或喝酒
But if you must lie, lie in the arms of the one you love.
真要说谎，在心爱的人怀中说
If you must steal, steal away from bad company.
真要偷窃，偷那些坏人的东西
If you must cheat, cheat death.
真要欺骗，就骗死神
And if you must drink...
真要喝酒…
drink in the moments that take your breath away.
就为心动的时刻畅饮
Did you just make that up?
那是你随口编的吗？
Make yourself at home.
请不用拘束
I'm gonna check on the risotto.
我去看看炖饭好了没
Look at this! Which one's the music?
看看这个！哪一个是音乐？
It does lights, too?
这也能控制灯光？
Let me help you out with that.
我来帮你吧
Now, this is nifty.
这真厉害
What are you doing?
你这是干嘛？
How does it work, exactly?
到底是怎么玩的？
Well, usually you have dinner, then you have dessert.
通常先吃晚饭，之后才吃甜点
No, I mean your thriving business.
我是说你伟大的事业
I don't do interviews.
我不接受访问
But if you'd like to get back to the evening, I'd be happy to sit and talk.
要是你想继续今晚的约会，我很乐意跟你聊
Great idea. You start.
好主意，你先说
Well, maybe I would if you weren't snarling.
你别那么大声我就说
What if I told you...
我告诉你...
that I know exactly what you do and how you do it?
我知道你是做什么的     也知道你怎么做
And I think it's despicable!
而我觉得那很卑鄙！
You know what? We might need to go out to dinner.
我们也许得出去用餐了
There's a great seafood restaurant I'd love to take you to.
我带你去一家很棒的海鲜餐厅
How about you just get a cleaver, butcher?
你干脆去买支屠刀吧，大屠夫
- Maybe I will! - What the hell is wrong with you?
也许我会！     你到底是怎么回事？
Nothing a front-page story can't cure.
头版报导就是证明
So that's what this is all about?
原来是这么一回事
Albert and Allegra on the front of your crap-ass newspaper?
原来是艾伯特跟奥丽格拉的新闻
- You put them there! - No, you did!
是你造成的！     不对，是你！
No, he did! The minute he called you!
是他，就从他找你的那一刻开始！
Dr. Hitch. Listen to me, papi.
情圣博士，听我说，老爹
I need to bring my partner, Amir, somewhere amazing for our anniversary.
我想带伴侣亚密去庆祝纪念日…
Maybe it's not your thing, but maybe it is.
也许这不是你的专长，也许是
What the hell are you talking about, Raoul?
你在说什么？
It's you, no?
这是你吧？
So, my friend, how was she? Pretty good?
朋友，她怎样？很赞吧？
How was she? I'll tell you! She was great!
怎样？她棒呆了！
Isn't that the Date Doctor?
那不是那个约会顾问吗？
- I'm telling you, that's him. - He doesn't look anything like him.
那一定就是他     看起来不像
- Excuse me. Do you know him? - No.
抱歉，你认识他吗？     不认识
I want you to look me in the eye and tell me that he did not hire you.
我要你看着我说，他没雇用你
Ma'am, I have never seen this man before in my life.
太太，我从来没见过这个男人
See you later, Tony.
待会见，东尼
Tony? You have got some serious explaining to do.
东尼？这下你得解释清楚了
Albert. Hitch. You all right?
艾伯特情圣，你还好吧？
I can't really talk right now. I'm kind of tied up.
我现在不能说话，我被人压着
One, two. On three.
数到三，一、二、三
Women will remain seated.
小姐们留在原座
Men will rotate to the left at the buzzer.
先生们轮流向左换位子
You get two minutes each, four minutes total.
每个人有两分钟，总共四分钟
So trade your talk time when you hear...
交换谈话时间请听…
the gong.
这个锣声
If it's mutual, you get numbers.
如果彼此合意，就留下电话
If not, better luck next time, okay?
如果不合，下次会更好
Ladies, take your seats.
小姐们，请就座
Case, you are a living testimonial to the triumph of hope over experience.
崔希，你是希望战胜经验的典范
Thanks for coming.
谢谢你肯来
I know it's lame. I'm sure it's the last thing you feel like doing.
我知道这很蠢，你很不喜欢这样
I really prefer Rachmaninoff to the heavier romantic composers.
我觉得拉赫曼尼诺夫很浪漫
But despite the pan-Germanic anti-Semitism...
撇开泛日耳曼的反犹太主义来说…
I'd still have to say my favorite is Wagner.
我还是得说我最喜欢华格纳
- Nice talking to you. - Thank you. Bye.
谈话愉快     谢谢你，拜
Bye.
拜
Excuse me.
抱歉
That's my seat, man.
那是我的位子
My name is Ron. I'm 28.
我叫朗恩，28岁
Albert Brennaman is a good man.
艾伯特是个好人
In fact, Albert Brennaman is a great man.
事实上，他是很棒的人
I just got out of a five-year relationship.
我才刚结束一段五年的感情
I'm a lot of fun at parties. I like dogs...
我喜欢参加派对、喜欢狗…
And then you're mad at me for what I do for a living?
所以你是气我的工作？
I've already got your number...
我已经有你的电话了…
so why don't you go consult your conscience?
你何不回去好好反省一下？
- Albert is in love with her. - Just like Sebastian?
艾伯特爱她     跟赛比一样？
- Is there a problem? - No, just one sec.
有问题吗？     没有，等一等
- What do you have against Allegra anyway? - Nothing.
你对奥丽格拉有什么不满？     没有
My interest is protecting women from assholes like you.
我想保护女人     远离你这种混蛋
I did ice climbing once.
我攀爬过冰崖
- You don't even know me. - And whose fault is that?
你根本不认识我     那是谁的错？
...the sun comes up, the ice really starts to fall apart.
太阳一出来，冰就裂了
I bet. I'm sorry.
我相信，抱歉
- Do you know this guy? - Apparently not.
你认识这人？     显然是不认识
You're in my seat.
你坐了我的位子
You really... I'm doing you a favor, believe me.
你...     我这是帮你忙，相信我
Basically, I like outdoor sports. But indoor sports have their place, too.
基本上，我喜欢户外运动     不过室内运动也不错
There are certain aspects of my job that are secretive.
我的工作有些部份要保密
And my job is to try to find the truth.
我的工作则是要挖掘真相
The truth? You wouldn't know the truth if it kicked you in the head.
你头撞坏了，根本搞不清真相
If Albert Brennaman has to take a fall for it, so be it.
若艾伯特因此受苦，那就算了
Why don't you say what's really pissing you off?
你为什么不说你在气什么？
I've been waiting to talk to her...
我一直等着跟她说话…
- You want to sit down? Here you go. Gong! - Thank you.
你想坐？坐吧，咚！     谢谢你
Excuse me.
抱歉
Hi. Actually, you're not supposed to move.
其实你不该移位，该他…
I'm Alex Hitchens. No, it's okay. Go.
我是情圣，没关系，继续
- I'm Casey. - Hi, Casey.
我是崔希     你好，崔希
I work for a small publishing house in the press department...
我在一家小出版社任职…
which isn't actually where I want to be. But it's a good house...
我不喜欢那份工作     但公司不错…
You handled me. You manipulated me.
你骗我，你唬弄我
You researched me and you showed me my great-grandfather's signature.
你找上我     还让我看曾曾祖父的签名
Wait. You're Ellis Island?
等等，艾利斯岛是你干的？
- I thought that was real sweet. - Thank you.
我觉得那很贴心     谢谢
Case, you're not helping.
你别帮倒忙
Excuse me, I'm on a date.
抱歉，我在约会
Does it ever occur to women that maybe a guy might like to have a plan...
女人有没有想过，男人会紧张…
because he's nervous?
所以要事先规划？
He's not sure that he could just walk up to you and you'd respond if he said:
他不确定直接表明心意会怎样…
"I like you."
“我喜欢你”
- That sounds good to me. - True, you can't tell them you like them.
我觉得很棒     不能跟女人说你喜欢她们
- I tried that. It didn't go well. - I've crashed and burned on that.
我试过，结果不怎样     我还因此受伤惨重
That is what you did, and I did like you!
你就这么做，而我也喜欢上你！
I just didn't know I was being worked over by some professional.
我没想到自己是被专家唬弄了
He doesn't have a badge.
他没别名牌
The only time he was sincere or spontaneous...
他唯一真诚、自在的时刻…
was when everything was going wrong or when you were stoned out of your head.
就是约会不顺或服药过量的时候
- I'm sorry to interrupt. Do I know you? - No, I don't think so.
抱歉打扰，我认识你吗？     我想你不认识
- You wanna see me be spontaneous? - Sure, you want a Benadryl?
你想看什么是自在吗？     当然，要喝过敏糖浆吗？
This is really kind of distracting. And I haven't gotten laid in a year!
这真令人抓狂     我已经一年没性生活了
We're sorry. Why don't you guys get back to your date?
对不起，你们回去约会吧
Or go somewhere.
不然就去别的地方
Maybe from the bank?
也许你是银行的人？
If this doesn't work out, call him. He might hook you up with Paris Hilton.
如果你约会没结果，找他     他会帮你搭上社交名媛
Wait, that's it. You're the Date Doctor, right?
我知道了，你是约会顾问
- You're the Date Doctor? - Do we have a problem here?
你就是那个约会顾问？     有问题吗？
Yeah, a big one! What the hell did I ever do to you?
问题大了！我哪里对不起你了？
Am I missing something?
我是不是没搞懂什么？
Sir, I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
先生，我得请你离开
Why don't you go hit a titty bar with your buddy Vance?
你去脱衣酒吧找你好朋友范斯吧
Wow.
天哪
I don't believe this.
我真不敢相信
That's your source?
那就是你的消息来源？
You buried yourself, Alex.
是你搞死了你自己
Then you weren't listening.
你根本没注意听
I heard every word.
我听得很清楚
You're a scam artist.
你是骗王之王
- You trick women into getting... - Into getting out of their own way...
欺骗女人…     让她们放下心防…
so great guys like Albert Brennaman have a fighting chance.
好让艾伯特这种好男人有机会
No, I want everybody to take a good look at this right now.
我要大家仔细看清楚
Because this right here...
因为这里发生的事…
this is exactly why falling in love is so goddamn hard.
就是因为这样恋爱才这么难
Sir, let's go. Now.
先生，请离场
And Vance Munson is a pig!
范斯孟森是一头猪！
And I refused to work with him.
我拒绝了他
You need to get your facts right.
你的消息应该要查证确实
It's because of jerks like him that I even have a job.
就是因为那种猪头我才有饭吃
Had a job.
曾经有饭吃
Can you believe that guy?
你相信那家伙吗？
Actually, I do.
其实我相信耶
You...
你...
complete me.
成就了我
- I might just have... - Shut up.
我可能只是…     闭嘴
Just shut up.
请你闭嘴
You had me at "hello."
你一开口就掳获了我
No comment.
无可奉告
This is off the record.
这不是采访
I came to apologize.
我是来道歉的
I made some assumptions about you...
我用一些错误的消息对你...
based on nothing, it turns out.
妄下论断
- I guess Casey's right. My best friend... - Don't worry about it. We're straight.
我想崔希说得对     别担心，我们扯平了
I should've asked you. But sometimes you're so guarded.
我应该先问过你     但你老是充满戒心
I just don't wanna be another reason for you to...
我不想成为另一个…
I'm not someone who likes to get involved past a certain point.
我在某个特定时间点之后     是不会吃回头草的
And that point was about a week ago.
而那个时间点     是大约一周前
Well, I just want to say I'm really sorry...
我只想告诉你，我很抱歉…
and I didn't mean to hurt you.
我无意伤害你
You didn't.
你没伤害到我
That's a relief.
那真令人欣慰
- Hey, fella. - Yeah, good. You?
老朋友     我很好，你呢？
What you got there?
你手上拿了什么？
This? I figured maybe if my heart stops beating, it wouldn't hurt so much.
这个？我想如果我死了，也许就不会心痛了
She hasn't called back?
她没回你电话？
You want some coffee?
要不要喝咖啡？
I want you to fix it.
我要你挽回一切
I got nothing, Albert.
我帮不了你了
You wanna do something? We should get out tonight.
要不要去玩？我们今晚出去玩
Honestly, I never knew I could feel like this.
没想到我也会有这种感觉
I swear I'm going out of my mind.
我陷入疯狂
I wanna throw myself off of every building in New York.
我想跳楼
I see a cab and I wanna dive in front of it, because then I'll stop thinking about her.
我还想跳到疾驶的计程车前     好让我停止想她
Look, you will. Just give it time.
你会的，再过些时候就行
That's just it. I don't want to.
问题就在这里，我不要那样
I've waited my whole life to feel this miserable.
我为了这种感觉等了一辈子
If this is the only way I can stay connected with her...
如果我只能跟她有这种关系…
then this is who I have to be.
我就想留住这种感觉
No, you don't. You can change, you can adapt.
你不会的，你会改变、适应
You can make it so you don't ever have to feel like this.
你能让自己永远不再心痛
Ever again.
永远不会
Oh, my God. You just don't get it, do you?
你就是不懂，对吧？
I get it.
我懂
Let me get this straight.
我就直接了当的说吧
You're selling this stuff, but you don't believe in your own product.
你做这行，却不相信自己的产品
- Love is my life. - No. Love is your job.
爱是我的生命     不，爱是你的工作
You wanna jump out a plane without a chute, be my guest.
你想从飞机上跳下来，随便你
But forgive me if I don't join you.
原谅我无法与你同行
This isn't about love for you at all, is it?
这不只因为爱吧？
This whole time, I thought I was the coward.
我还以为我才是懦夫呢
- Where you going? - Skydiving.
你要去哪？     跳伞
Taxi!
计程车！
Mr. Hitchens.
情圣先生
Miss Cole, thank you very much for seeing me.
珂儿小姐，谢谢你肯见我
You said it was a matter of life and death.
你说这是生死攸关的事
That man would've sold his soul to make you happy.
那个男人愿意为你出卖灵魂
So what does that make you, the devil?
那你是什么？魔鬼？
My job is not to deceive, Miss Cole. It's to create opportunities.
我不欺骗，而是创造机会
Like the boardroom.
就像那场会议
- Would you have noticed him otherwise? - Yes.
换做其他情况你会注意他吗？     会
- Really? - Eventually.
真的？     终究会的
Maybe.
也许会吧
How did you know all that stuff about me?
你怎么会知道我的事？
Well, you really did your homework.
你果然做足了研究
Like at boarding school when everyone used to tease me because I couldn't whistle.
像寄宿学校的事     大家都笑我不会吹口哨
And having him dance like a buffoon knowing that I can't dance, either.
还教他笨手笨脚的跳舞     你知道我也不会跳舞
Then telling him to drop mustard on his shirt, so I'd feel less like a dork.
还叫他把芥末弄到衣服上     好让我不会太糗
That was all you, right?
那都是你教他的吧？
No. Hell, no.
不对，根本不是
That was him?
那是他自己？
That's got Albert written all over it.
艾伯特就是那个样子
Did you put him up to the inhaler?
你没叫他用吸入器？
Stop it. He did not show you that.
拜托，他没让你看到那个吧
He chucked it right before he kissed me.
他在吻我之前，随手丢了它
So, wait...
等等…
that stuff worked for you?
你喜欢那种样子？
It was adorable.
那样很可爱
What did you do?
你做了什么？
Nothing.
什么都没做
Absolutely nothing.
绝对没有
That's good.
太好了
- This was your plan the whole time? - Albert.
这就是你的计划？     艾伯特
You sail off into the sunset with my girl?
你跟我的女人出海看日落？
You were like a brother to me!
你就像我的兄弟一样！
- He came here for you. - Who?
他是为了你而来的     谁？
The guy you're choking.
你正在掐的这个人
- I love you.
我爱你     我爱你
I really love you.
我真的爱你
- I love you more. - I love you more. I really do.
我更爱你     我才更爱你，真的
I got somewhere I gotta go.
我还有别的地方要去…
- Yeah, who is it? - Hitch.
来了！是谁？     情圣
Can I talk to you?
能跟你谈谈吗？
What?
干嘛？
You almost hit me.
你差点打到我
Look, I just wanted to stop by, basically.
我只是想过来，基本上…
See, this is the thing.
我是想说
This is weird. I don't have me behind the door, you know.
这真怪，没人指导我，所以…
Close your mouth.
把嘴巴闭上
Because I knew at some point I'd be...
因为我知道我有些时候…
right here. But I thought that...
你知道，就是这样     但我想…
everything would come out, but it's like...
我以为不会有问题     但这真是…
That's throwing me off.
我不太自在
- Can we close the door? - What?
能不能关上门？     什么？
I'm sorry. Just, can we... I just need...
抱歉，能不能？我需要…
- Are you serious? - No, just like this.
你当真？     这样就好
What do you want, Hitch?
你要什么？
You.
你
For a whole lot of reasons that don't make any sense to me.
为了很多连我都莫名其妙的理由
I mean, what, we've been on three dates?
我们只约过三次会吧？
See, that's what's crazy.
那是最疯狂的地方了
That's what's crazy, because I know.
因为我打从心底知道
I know deep...
我打从心底…
like just down, just in this area...
就在这里、这个区域…
that I just know...
我就是知道…
that I want...
我想要…
I want to be miserable.
我想要为情所苦
Like, really miserable.
悲惨到底
Because, hey...
因为…
if that's what it takes for me to be happy then...
那是唯一能让我快乐的办法…
Wait, that didn't come out right.
我说得不太对
What the hell is wrong with you?
你是怎么回事？
- Nothing! - No, not you.
我没事！     不，不是你
I'm talking to me.
我是在跟我自己说话
Alex Hitchens, Tom Reda.
情圣，汤姆雷达
I'll just put this in the car.
我把这拿去放车里
Maybe it's like what you said.
也许就跟你说的一样
We should just both go our separate ways and then we'll do just fine.
我们应该各过各的生活，那样我们也会过得很好
What if fine isn't good enough?
如果“好”还不够呢？
What if I want extraordinary?
如果我想要“特好”呢？
No such thing.
没有那种事
I'm just as scared as you are, Sara.
莎拉，我跟你一样害怕
But I'm right here, and our time is right now.
但是我来了，一切就在现在
Well, what about before?
那之前呢？
I am a guy. Since when do we get anything right the first time?
我是男人，男人说话有对过吗？
I'm a realist, and I know what love does to people.
那我很务实     我知道爱情对人会有什么影响
- No, you don't. - Keys.
你不知道     钥匙
There you go. Right here.
请上车
I don't know who this is, and I don't care.
我不知道这是谁，我也不在乎
What I do know is he'll never feel about you the way that I do.
我只知道他对你不会跟我一样
- You know how to drive a stick? - Both of you, shut up!
你会开手排车吗？     你们都给我闭嘴
- You okay? - Yeah. No, I'm fine.
你还好吧？     我很好
You'll never be fine, and neither will I!
你不会好的，我也一样
Maybe I should drive.
也许该由我来开车
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
你是不是想自杀啊？
If that's what it takes.
如果必要的话
Sara, what happened?
怎么了？
- He jumped on the car. - Why?
他跳上车子     为什么？
Because that's what people do.
人谈恋爱就是会这样
They leap and hope to God they can fly.
会雀跃     还希望自己会飞
Because otherwise...
不然的话…
we just drop like a rock...
我们会像石头般掉落…
wondering the whole way down:
坠落时一路想着…
"Why in the hell did I jump?"
“我为什么要跳？”
But here I am, Sara, falling.
但是我在这里     坠落地面
And there's only one person that makes me feel like I can fly.
而唯一让我感觉自己会飞的人
That's you.
就是你
So, you kind of like me?
所以你有点喜欢我？
No.
不
I love you.
我爱你
I love you, and I knew it from the first...
我爱你，我从一开始就…
If I say it back now, it'll sound so stupid.
如果我也说一样的话就很蠢了
This is the guy I was telling you about. Hitch, that's my sister, Maria.
这是我跟你提过的那个人     情圣，这是我妹，玛莉亚
And that's her husband, Tom.
那位是她老公，汤姆
Her husband.
她老公
Where's your date?
你的伴呢？
Don't have one.
我没有伴
I know. Shocking, huh?
我知道，令人惊讶吧？
Oh, my God!
老天，我的妈呀！
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Grandma, what happened?
阿嬷，怎么回事？
This young lady just saved my life.
这位小姐刚刚救了我一命
Ask her to dance.
请她跳舞吧
Well, if you insist.
如果你坚持的话
- I'm Casey. - Charles Wellington.
我是崔希     查尔斯威灵顿
- And this... - Forget it. Just go.
这位是…     算了，去吧
Basic principles:
基本原则…
There are none.
根本没有原则